[Music]
Hello, everyone.
TDSW YouTube Channel.
This will be the sixth episode of Getting started with GLSL on TouchDesigner.
Thank you for watching!
This time with uv.
public
It's more like a pixelated effect.
We will create a Mosaic effect.
When you press the button, it changes to this.
It's like this.
This time, we'll do it.
First, use uv to change the resolution according to the amount of change.
Adjusting the Position of Getting Color When Changing Resolution
At the end of the day, though, this is something we'll have to adjust in CHOP.
Create a parameter that changes with the amount of change by turning the button on or off.
We're going to do this.
So let's get to it.
It's good.
Place the GLSL TOP as usual
In this case, we'll use images.
Or a banana, for that matter.
It's better to have color in all of them.
I will use flowers.
I've got this hooked up.
Also.
Display GLSL in VSCode
I want the color to be this texture color.
It goes like this.
First thing's first.
vec2 p = vUV.st
Put uv into this first
Declare the amount of change.
Let it be float d
Let's say it's 10.
I'd like to start by changing the resolution in the x direction.
p.x = floor(p.x)
And it goes like this.
It's called vUV.st here.
I'll put a p.
It's like this.
Multiply this by the value of d
Like this.
Here's what we're doing.
It's probably easier to see it by the color of the uv.
I'm going to show you a little bit of that.
vec4 color vec4
This way, sir.
0.0 with a p in.
Well, here's what it looks like.
What does this mean?
You should get out the TOP To and look at the numbers.
It might be easier to understand.
Like this.
There's a zero at the beginning of the 10-split section.
And all the rest of it has one in it.
It's like this.
Like this.
There's no red color here because it's zero.
that is to say
And then there's this one more.
I'm going to do this thing where I repeat it 10 times.
It's like compressing it once and then stretching it out.
If I do this, the display shows 0 to 1 this time.
It's like what you see on CHOP To over here.
It's pretty much like a staircase, isn't it?
Commenting this out.
It's going to be smooth.
This is the process we're going through right now.
Like this.
If we put this back into texture
Here's what happened.
Oh, I think I'd better go with "d" here.
D.
Now we're going to add it in the y direction.
Like this.
You can see how it's pixellated in this way.
Let's do this one more time.
You can see it here.
It's like this.
These large blocks of pixels.
You can see it's made.
The r's are in this kind of staircase shape.
If you look at this in Crop called Column.
And now the g's.
You can see that it's a staircase.
This will bring the colors back to their original texture again.
It looks like this.
This one block is the original pixel, the
It's the same as 1280x720 and it's now 16:9.
For example, if you want to make this a square.
You may want to adjust the Aspect Ratio.
The floor is what we call the ground.
It's called truncation.
If you round this up to the nearest "ceil," you can use
It goes something like this.
I don't think it would affect my appearance that much.
I don't want to round up, I want to get the middle number.
Just once, right here.
I'd like to take the value between floor and ceil
Divide it by two.
The y-direction also divides 2 and
Let's do this.
Like this.
This way, I hope it's a perfect fit.
Now we can change the numbers here a bit.
So the mosaic changes in size.
Here's what it looks like.
Now we just need to add this part of the parameter to the
I will try to give it to GLSL.
The use of the UNIFORM
Maybe we should do a uAmount or something this time.
This is what it looks like when it's in.
I've already declared it.
Load UniformNames If you click here, you can use the
I thought you were already in here.
0.5 is too small, so you can put in 50 or something like that.
It comes out like this.
Now I'm going to give you this value.
I'd like to be able to generate it with a button
First, place the Button
Button
In.
null1
I want to create an on and off state.
Here you go.
I'm using this state as Toggle Down
And the rest is in the meantime.
I'd like to put some numbers in.
First, add a Lag CHOP.
We'll make sure the movement is smooth.
In this case, it's 0.5, 0.5.
Whatever you want to call it, but I'm going to use a number like this
Add a Math CHOP here.
Determine the Range
I'm sure you can adjust this place later on yourself, too.
Let's say you get a number like 500 to 400.
The value of this Null.
I'll put it in this uAmount.
Like this.
This way, here we are.
You can see it's pixellated.
Let's look at it a little larger.
Enlarge this and get it out.
Give me a button.
It's like this.
When this is animated.
I think you can see the black stuff on the edges.
Maybe I should put "Mirror" here instead of "Zero".
I'll put the Mirror in it.
If you do that.
I'm guessing that when you moved it around, you couldn't see the black areas here.
Now it responds to the button.
We've got a mosaic effect.
That's it for this one.
About twice a month at TDSW.
We're running live streaming workshops on the weekend.
Tickets are available through Petix and Eventbrite!
Also, TDSW uses Patreon
There are currently three plans available
You can find these links in the video overview section of the video
Check it out if you'd like.
So thank you for watching.
If you like it, please subscribe to our channel!
goodbye
[Music]